

Tucson, Arizona 85719, +16024756353, farazmohseni@outlook.com

### PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

I consider myself to be creative, independent and ambitious. I'm currently double majoring in computer science and mathematics with minors in philosophy, data science and economics. I enjoy thinking big about major social issues using my background in mathematics and programming. I am experienced in software development, web design and data visualization.

#### **EDUCATION**

Bachelor of science: Computer science

May 2023

University of Arizona, Tucson, Arizona

This degree focused on building a solid understanding of various computer science domains. I took additional electives in web design, data science and algorithms.

I was active in the Honors college, philosophy and debate club.

Cumulative GPA: 3.441/4 Major GPA: 3.422/4

Bachelor of science: Mathematics

May 2023

University of Arizona, Tucson, Arizona

This degree focused on discrete mathematics, probability and statistics.

### **EXPERIENCE**

Independent Researcher

July 2021 - Current

University of Arizona | Tucson, Arizona, USA

- I worked with professor Surdeanu on an original research proposal I had. I used text retrieval and NLP methods along with ML algorithms to automate news agency bias classification.
- This work is expected to be published.

Undergraduate Teaching Assistant (CSC 245: Discrete mathematics)

July 2021 - Current

University of Arizona | Tucson, Arizona, USA

• I helped students with understanding the content, hosted review sessions, answered questions on piazza and graded guizzes, exams and homework.

# Undergraduate Research Assistant

January 2021 - Current

University of Arizona | Tucson, AZ, USA

 Worked with professor Heileman's group on a variety of projects including: optimized curriculm design, data visualization for education administration and University-based crypto currency.

### Business Intelligence Intern

December 2021 - January 2022

Green proposition | Ras Al Khaimah, Ras Al Khaimah, UAE

- Identified process and business efficiency improvements through application of data science and BI model development.
- Prepared and delivered technical and training documentation.
- Recommended actions based on synthesized business intelligence and trend data.

Polyup | Tucson, Arizona, USA

- I developed mathematics content based on the k-12 curriculum and attended relevant meetings to discuss contests, quality controls and survey design.
- My proposals for recruitment strategy and growth strategy were well received by the managers and they decided to experiment with my suggestions.

# **SKILLS**

Machine learning, Software development, Data analytics, Data visualization, Creative problem solving, Algorithm design

### **TOOLS AND LANGUAGES**

**Expert knowlege:** Java, Python, Scala, d3.js, JavaScript, scikit-learn, numPy, Matplotlib, CSS, HTML, C, C++, bash scripting, SVG

Advanced knowledge: R, Prolog

### **AWARDS**

#### ASA 2022 DataFest best visualization award

Students are given real-world data in a 37 hour contest and the best projects are given awards.

#### **Global Wildcat Award:**

This scholarship is given to top incoming international students and is worth 30000\$ per academic year.

### Deans list with distinction:

Recognizing students with a GPA of 4.00

### First level honors:

This award is given to students meeting honors college requirements for the first 60 units of their studies

#### Iranian National mathematics Olympiad silver medal:

A highly competitive and prestigious high school student contest focusing on creative problem solving.

# IGO advanced level bronze medal:

This is an international geometry contest for all geometry enthusiasts especially students in grades 11 and 12 of K-12.

#### **LANGUAGES**

# Persian:

Native language

#### English:

Full working proficiency as demonstrated in TOEFL test scores